Okay, it's time to complete the Rag workflow in our Jupyter Lab on day 2.3.
이제 2일째 주피터 연구실에서 래그 워크플로우를 끝낼 시간이에요 3번요
We've got this function Getprice that you are very familiar with now, which is the super simple one
이제 익숙해진 함수 Getprice가 있습니다 아주 간단한 것으로
that takes a string and plucks out the floating point number from it.
문자열에서 부동 소수점 수를 뽑아내는 거죠
And now the function for GPT for mini.
이제 미니를 위한 GPT 함수인데요
What we do is we say documents and prices is fine similares of items.
서류와 가격은 괜찮다고 하죠 비슷한 물건들을요
So it's passed in an item.
항목을 전달하는 거죠
We find what is similar to that item.
비슷한 물건을 찾아냈어요
And then we call OpenAI chat dot completions dot create.
OpenAI 채팅 .완료 .Create라고 하죠
We're going to specify GPT for mini.
미니를 위해 GPT를 지정할게요
We're going to pass in the messages using the function messages for.
함수 메시지를 이용해 메시지를 전달할 거예요
And we'll give it a seed.
씨앗을 뿌릴 거예요
We want back five tokens.
5토큰을 돌려줘요
And what comes back we say response dot choices zero dot message content.
응답은 .선택 0.Message content라고 하죠
And then we call get price on the reply to pluck out the number from that.
getPrice에 응답해 거기서 번호를 추출하는 거죠
And that's all there should be to it.
그게 전부여야 해요
Let's try it out on one before we before we go crazy here.
미치기 전에 한 번 시험해 보죠
Uh, so we're going to say, um, let's see, uh, GPT four mini rag and we will pass in the test one
GPT 4 미니 래그를 보고 방금 본 클러치 테스트를 통과할
that we just looked at that clutch thing.
거예요
Uh, and let's see what we get back.
Get in get을 해 보죠
Uh, we get back $201 and 45, uh, and let's see what what actually, it should be test one dot price.
201달러와 45달러를 환불받았고 이제 get att.s.pr.를 테스트해야 해요
Uh, it's pretty close.
거의 비슷해요
It's pretty close.
비슷해요
Look at that.
보세요
Uh, so, uh, it's great the way it's so very quick to run.
아주 빠르게 달릴 수 있어서 좋아요
And you can see everything that's happened there.
거기서 일어난 모든 일을 볼 수 있어요
It looked up five similar items.
비슷한 아이템이 다섯 개 검색됐어요
It constructed a query, uh, for OpenAI that incorporated the context of those five similar items in
오픈AI를 위한 쿼리를 구성했습니다. 유사한 항목 5개를 오픈AI에 보낸 프롬프트에요.
And then it made the call, got back the response, and stripped out the price and told us how much
그런 다음 전화를 걸었고 응답이 왔어요 가격을 줄이고 가격을 알려줬죠
it cost.
꽤 비슷했어요
So with that.
자, 됐어요
Do you remember our tester from before?
전에 왔던 테스터 기억나요?
Our framework for testing the 250, uh, top, uh, test results.
250개의 테스트 결과를 시험할 프레임워크예요
And you remember where we came out with our model?
우리 모형이 어디서 나왔는지 기억해요?
Uh, it's definitely scary to think.
생각만 해도 무서워요
Okay, but but now we've given a huge benefit to the frontier model.
하지만 개척지 모델에 큰 혜택을 줬잖아요
Uh, how can it do with this?
이걸로 뭘 할 수 있죠?
So we can run it at this point, and we will see how it does?
이 시점에서 실행하면 어떻게 되는지 볼까요?
Uh, and off it will go while it's doing that.
그렇게 하는 동안 작동할 거예요
And you can already see a lot of greens in here.
벌써 많은 녹색이 보이시죠
Uh, it's, of course, getting a lot of information.
물론 많은 정보를 얻죠
I want to show you what I've done over here in the agents folder.
에이전트 폴더에서 제가 한 걸 보여드리고 싶어요
Uh, in the agents folder, I have made something called Frontier Agent, and this is now taking exactly
에이전트 폴더에 프론티어 에이전트라는 걸 만들었어요 이건 우리가 방금 살펴본
the code we've just looked through and turning it into production ready code.
바로 그 코드를 프로덕션 준비 코드로 바꾸고 있죠
And the way I've done that is that you can see from this sea of red that I've been adding in comments,
보다시피 빨간 바다를 보면 주석을 추가하고 있어요 중요한 단계죠
which is an important step and I've been putting in type hints so that we get to see exactly what we're
힌트도 입력했어요 우리가 뭘 하는지 정확히 알 수 있게요 get
doing along the way.
it
And you can see as we go through it's it's very simple.
보시면 아시겠지만 아주 간단해요
It's the same stuff.
똑같은 거예요
Make context creates the context to insert into the prompt messages for creates the message list in
컨텍스트를 만드는 것은 열린 인공지능 형식의 메시지 목록을 만들기 위해 프롬프트 메시지를 삽입할 컨텍스트를
that open AI format.
만드는 것이죠
You may be familiar with this way of specifying putting a comment against each of the parameters and
익숙하실 텐데요 각각의 매개 변수에 주석을 넣고 반환되는 것을 지정하는
then what gets returned.
방법이죠
You can also see some more sophisticated type hints here that specify when we have lists of strings,
보다 복잡한 형식 힌트도 보실 수 있습니다 문자열 목록이 언제 있는지 지정하고 문자열 키와
and a list of dictionaries with the key of a string and a value of a string, and then find similares,
문자열 값을 가진 사전 목록도 지정하고 유사한 걸 찾아요 주어진 것과 유사한 아이템 목록을
which returns a list of items similar to the given one by looking in chroma get price.
반환하는 거죠 chroma getPrice를 보면서요
We know it well.
잘 알죠
And then finally the price method here.
마지막으로 가격 메서드예요
So all of this is now part of a class called Frontier Agent, which is a subclass of my superclass agent,
프론티어 에이전트라는 클래스의 일부예요 제 슈퍼클래스 에이전트의 서브클래스죠
and it's packaged up nicely so that we can use it for production purposes.
잘 포장돼 있어서 생산 목적으로 사용할 수 있어요
And so again, as part of your learning as you as you see that difference between moving from a Jupyter
다시 한 번 학습의 일부로 주피터 세상에서 생산 준비 코드로의
world into more production ready code, this is the kind of jump you would make.
이동을 보면 이런 종류의 점프를 하게 되죠
And typically you'd be building this in a tool like VSCode or in PyCharm or something like that.
일반적으로 VSCode나 PyCam 같은 도구에서 이걸 빌드하죠
I tend to love PyCharm, but you can also use JupyterLab for this as we've got it right here.
전 파이컴을 좋아하지만 주피터랩을 이용해도 돼요 여기 있으니까요
You can write code in Jupyter Lab, but there are ideas that are designed for this kind of thing and
주피터 랩에서 코드를 쓸 수 있지만 이런 걸 위해 설계되고 더 좋게 만드는 아이디어가
make it better.
있어요
And we'll do stuff like filling in your, your, your prompts for your for what comments to write and
어떤 코멘트를 쓸지 프롬프트 같은 것도 채워 넣고요
So it's worth using an IDE when you get to this point.
이 지점까지 왔다면 IDE를 사용하는 게 좋아요.
All right.
좋아요
Hopefully I've jabbered away for long enough to see if we're doing well here.
제가 너무 떠들었나 봐요
It's getting close.
거의 다 왔어요
And there we have it.
다 됐어요
Okay, so here's what we notice.
네, 이걸 보세요
First of all, it is substantially better than GPT four mini and GPT four without Rag.
우선 GPT 4 미니와 래그 없이도 훨씬 좋은 차예요
We have moved the needle in a big way, but we're still at the point that our fine tuned frontier model
바늘을 크게 움직였지만 여전히 우리가 배치한 미세 조정 모델이
that we deployed up there is working better.
더 잘 작동하는 상태예요
So we still managed to beat even a rag pipeline based GPT four.
랙 파이프라인 기반의 GPT 4조차도 이겼어요
But it is great to see that the Rag pipeline does well and gets this close.
래그 파이프라인이 잘 작동해서 이렇게 가까워진 걸 보니 좋네요
So and you can see what looks like a beautiful chart here.
여기 아름다운 해도가 보이시죠
Uh, so that was great fun.
정말 재미있었어요
Uh, and I hope you've enjoyed that and see the same thing.
여러분도 즐거우셨길 바라고 같은 걸 보셨길 바라요
And do spend time looking through this code, see the prompts that are created, and print out some
이 코드를 훑어보며 생성된 프롬프트를 보고 일부를
of these prompts and satisfy yourself that we've basically, uh, in a more, more of a manual way.
프린트해 자신을 만족시키세요 기본적으로 좀 더 수동적인 방법으로요
We have done what exactly what Lang chain was automating for us before with with its wrapper code.
랭 체인이 자동화한 걸 정확히 했어요 래퍼 코드로요
We have gone out there, we've taken an item, we've found five similar items.
현장에 가서 물건을 하나 가져왔고 비슷한 물건을 다섯 개 찾았어요
We've packaged that up into some context.
그걸 몇 가지 컨텍스트에 포장했어요
And that's what we've sent to GPT four.
GPT 4에 보낸 자료예요
And that's given us significantly better results than when we didn't do that.
그렇게 하지 않았을 때보다 훨씬 좋은 결과를 얻었죠
Another thing to experiment with, of course I tried.
실험해볼 만한 또 다른 방법이죠 물론 시도는 해봤어요
I was passing in five.
5분 후에 지나갔어요
Results.
결과요
That is what you would call a hyperparameter.
하이퍼파라미터라고 부르는 거예요
We can explore what would happen if you make that ten.
10점이 되면 어떻게 될지 알아보죠
What would happen if you make it two?
두 개면 어떻게 될까요?
Having it at five means that this is still super cheap.
5달러면 정말 싼 거예요
It's a cent or two to run all of this.
1, 2센트면 다 운영할 수 있어요
Of course you should.
당연히 그래야죠
You should check for yourself in case pricing may vary, but.
가격이 다를 수 있으니 직접 확인해 보세요
But it's very cheap.
하지만 아주 싸요
Um, if you make it ten, then it's going to start to.
10분으로 하면 그렇게 될 거예요
It will cost double that.
두 배는 더 들 거예요
Uh actually not not less than double that, but it will cost a little bit more.
less는 아니지만 비트 요금은 좀 더 들 거예요
And so it's worth, uh, um, experimenting with these things within reason and see what you think,
그러니 합당한 범위 내에서 실험해 보고 어떻게 반응하는지
how it does.
봐야죠
Anyway, with that, that concludes our rag pipeline, and I will see you for the next part, which
어쨌든 이것으로 래그 파이프라인은 끝났습니다 다음 부분에서 뵙죠
is when we move to 2.4 and start talking about random forests again and ensemble models.
2로 이동할 때요 4번, 다시 아무 숲이나 얘기하기 앙상블 모델 얘기하기 시작하세요
See you then.
그때 봐요